It's all good.
It's all good. The Junkyard Love
Podcast.
>> [music]
>> 5
3 to the junkyard. I need to like get
stop our momentum so many times, but uh
good morning, brother. It's
>> [laughter]
>> It's uh
It's wonderful to to have you on here
again, man. Uh if anybody who is
listening remembers Tim from before, you
can go check our old episode. I'm sure
we both changed much since then, but
it's still I still I still remember
being a wonderful time. It was probably
what?
5 6 years ago? 5 years ago?
Yeah. Probably like
Yeah, at least 4 years ago. It was It
was minute. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, I'm I'm glad that you I'm glad
that we've been talking again, and I'm
glad that we decided to do another a do
another episode. Um you sent me I was
kind of like poking your brain last
night, kind of what
you know, what do you want to talk
about? What what are we thinking about?
And and I woke up this morning to what
you were what you were thinking.
>> to do it. That's so perfect. So
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. I
>> [clears throat]
>> I I can't wait. Uh dude, so I I think
where I would like to start I'll
probably weave in what we just talked
about cuz that's already good. But um
>> [clears throat]
>> I suppose like
Welcome to the Junkyard Love Podcast.
Welcome back to the Junkyard Love
Podcast, Mr. Tim. Um
thank you for your time. I'm What I want
to ask you
in regards to what we were talking about
and what you sent me last night, what's
been on your mind lately, man? What have
you been thinking about? Like what's uh
when you're like, "Man, I want to come
chat about this thing." What's kind of
the What's kind of the crux of it?
What's been on your mind?
Um
Honestly, it's um it's probably just
uh
connecting or reconnecting with uh
you know, friends of mine that um
that I know are on this path, basically.
Um and just, you you making sure there's
like that
there's a thread there
Um whether that's uh for
um
like just reconnection or in this case
reconnection
because we haven't chatted forever
but also just to you know, strengthen
the bond between you know,
uh
in this case like friends that
are actually like on the same path or
similar paths.
What what do you what do you mean by
path?
Um
like
probably just the you know, it's it's
not just like self um
you know, bettering self which I know
you've been a proponent of for a long
time.
Um I think it's also just um
there's I feel like there's a
spirituality aspect as well.
Not necessarily like religion or
anything like that but kind of with the
with the um
the way one thinks when uh
you know, you're you're trying to
basically you know, better oneself what
through like meditation or you know,
yoga or working out, diet, all these
things. It's just like a way of a way of
life and a way of thinking that
um
I think
it's similar
probably to us but also just you know, a
lot of other people and I've just been
on this path of
kind of um
I guess curating
a friend a friend group and a community
um
that are on that same wavelength. Mhm.
And just just really trying to see like
where everyone's at and like the
similarities and and you know, what your
path looks like and how do you how
you've gotten there and
you know, other friends as well that are
you know, on various various uh you
know, stages of this this kind of like
renewal and self self-awareness that
we're on.
Yeah. Yeah, I totally hear that man. I
mean dude, I what I I feel I feel pretty
spoiled that I have a podcast that I'm
able to have like
like an opportunity to hey man, let's
set aside 2 hours and just chat about
like what we've been what we've been
going through lately. And it's just like
this open door. I mean we could all we
could all pick up the phone and stuff. I
mean we try to call each other a few
weeks few months ago or whatever and
it's just like life is busy. We all know
how it is, but I I feel like spoiled to
be able to have this podcast that I can
just like let's just set aside a time
and we'll record the whole thing and we
could share it with other people and
they could like relate to it and
whatever. So yeah man, it's a
I was just talking with my friend Trey
on on a couple episodes ago and
we were talking about how difficult it
can be to
um
you know, connect with people who are
only connected to like a version of your
past that you don't really feel that
you're carrying around much anymore. Um
you know, like our example was you know,
if you used to party party a ton or
whatever
and then you kind of like are not really
into that much anymore and then you hang
out with people and that's kind of all
they remember of you and you're like,
man, but like don't you want to talk
about like what what else has been up,
you know? Like what
What have you been aiming towards, you
know? Like haven't you haven't you had
some sort of maturation cuz for me I
feel like every day has been like some
growth thing or you know, and so yeah,
absolutely man. It's it's really great
to
it's great to connect with friends who
are thinking about the future and
they're thinking about like how to
whatever their version of it, how to
better themselves, how to be
introspective. I think it's like
you know, I hate to I hate to do like
the
the world seems like it's crazy these
days cuz it's like, you know, just the
news is always going to tell you that.
But in a lot of ways it's like, you
know,
we do need we do we do need some
aspirations towards different
conversations and different ways of
looking at things. And so, you know,
that's what I mean
I'm sure you probably listen to podcasts
and things like that that you want to
hear people talking like that. You want
to hear people like being introspective.
You want to hear people who are trying
to be growth mindset, who are
um you know, not accepting what what
happened to them or what their past was
or who they were before as a solid
figure, you know, it's like we can grow
and grow and expand and
become new versions of ourselves day in
and day out.
Yeah.
Well, it's it's been especially with
technology, it's been kind of wild um
because you like you're saying with
podcasts like there's like these
different versions of like self-growth
and stuff and
you you like you you know, we grew up
kind of in this this this era where you
know, you're still kind of just flying
without any real influence besides your
friends and family. And then, you know,
you just you know, like you're saying
you party like crazy or or not, but you
know, in this case, you know, I think
both of us had a pretty good pretty good
run at it. And uh um you know, and then
later like for me it's like yeah, like
you're you find like some podcasts like
oh, this this guy's a dude, you know,
cuz maybe you don't feel like you're
you're you've just been feeling like
you're being a piece of piece of
for a long time. Like I mean being more
of a man. And then you're like it's
almost like the the the like you you can
go like you're like right over here,
then you're like way over Hey everybody,
this episode was recorded while I was
working overseas on a cruise ship
actually. So, this exact moment while
Tim was talking, a very loud alarm went
off. And there's also a couple moments
in this episode, I think only two more
times where the captain starts speaking
over the intercom and another alarm goes
off. I think I edited all that out, but
if there is a sudden moment where it
seems like I'm just cutting him off in
the middle of his sentence or vice
versa, it's just because I stitched it
together just so you guys don't have to
listen to a loud alarm. So, not an ad
break. I don't do ads on the podcast,
never have. Uh this is just me saying I
love you. And I hope you're doing
awesome. And I really appreciate you
listening to the show. And if you want
to hear some more, maybe subscribe and
like and all that stuff. So, I
appreciate you listening. Back to the
show. Yeah, okay. So, yeah, talking
about the pendulum swing of
of like the push towards towards
self-development. Um
I think you know, I'm with where I
talked about this before, but you know,
my origination when I first started this
podcast was that same sort of stuff. I
was
listening to a bunch of people have
perspectives that I just didn't have
anybody in my life to feed me those
perspectives perspectives before. I
would hear things or I'd hear, you know,
just like
men that I didn't realize I looked up to
as much as I did on just podcasts. Some
dude just BSing and he says something 2
and 1/2 hours in
about his life and how he learned this
thing and I'm like, "Dude, I never
thought about that way. That's actually
pretty cool." And I could I could
dissect that, take that from that
podcast that I'm just casually listening
to, and kind of run it through my own
internal dialogue, and see how it fits
in my own life experience.
And
you know, that that that's how we grow,
for sure. You know, like if we don't
have examples around us,
how do we aspire to be anything? So, we
don't you know,
like like you read books and it and it
opens your mind. When I was, you know,
mid-teenagers, I got into
self-development books and stuff like
that because
those were just perspectives I had never
heard before. They would blow my
freaking mind.
And so, yeah, I think it's cool that
podcasts are like that. I mean, as much
as podcasts can also be
so many other things. It's the
entertainment and and poop jokes and and
Yeah. And even doesn't all have to be
serious. Like, but uh it is it is a
pretty cool opportunity to just
hear different perspectives and
and then most importantly be open to
those new perspectives, yeah. You know.
For sure. Yeah. Um
So,
you were mentioning like the feminine
feminine and masculine stuff. As as you
as a man,
as you've gotten older,
how have you kind of understood your
relationship with kind of like
femininity and masculinity? Like,
in in regards to kind of like your
internal conversation with yourself.
Like, you're walking on the spiritual
path. We were just kind of talking about
how you kind of have to be gentle with
yourself. There is times, paradoxically,
where you have to go, "Hey, man, let's
go. Let's get after it. We got work to
do. Like, this thing needs finished.
We've got a deadline." But, then there's
also this, you know, pendulum swing
again where you have to have gentleness.
Like, what I don't know. What What's
that been like for you?
Um it's been pretty wild, actually. Um
It went from like we're talking about
the pendulum. It went from like
having being so rigid uh
and being just like a total dude. Just
like this is it's just how everything
has to just be logic, you know? If it
doesn't make sense, then, you know, why
what are you talking about? What do you
mean you feel that way? What are you
talking about?
>> [snorts]
>> Um
to
really taking time to uh think about
for me it was more like um
more of a spiritual awakening for me.
And, you know, like you're saying,
through like books and um
you know, prayer and other things on my
end.
Um and and other other friends of mine
that are um
that I really confide in for this kind
of stuff. Um
I realized that
there's like everything everything has a
duality.
Like, everything.
And
to really be a whole, you need you need
the feminine. You need a man needs the
feminine. If and to the women, the women
need the masculine. Like, to really be a
whole, like, you know, spiritual being.
Uh I think we're created that way. Um
and maybe that's part of life is what
kind of one of my questions is, you
know, that that's part of the journey is
to like master
um both sides of that. To really kind of
like, you know, people might call
enlightenment or whatever you want to
call it. I just think it's just, you
know, kind of being in a back making
yourself back whole is kind of um what
my interpretation of it has kind of
been. And the key to that for me has
been
the
there's the action, the the masculine,
and then there's um
you know, the the giving, and then
there's the receiving, the feminine, you
know, and just like um being open to not
action and receiving, you know, whether
that's a download,
whether that's um
you know, um
a sign or a symbol or, you know,
whatever it is you're waiting for.
Um
the for me that's been huge is like
actually like instead of trying to
create the storm, you know,
just it was being in it, being in the
storm. And just like you create the
storm, oh, you can also be in it and
wait for, you know, what you're you're
trying to create to kind of come and
come to be.
Um
And that's been pretty crazy
um because
depending on, you know, if you're male
or female, like
there's the impatience, right? Of
you're wanting to take action. You're
like, I know, put me in. This is this is
my thing. I like I need to take action.
And then like, you know, whether it's
God or you know, spirit, whatever you
whatever your
your self, you know, whatever your
thoughts on that are, it's it comes into
a uh
little bit of a paradox where you're
like, no, this is actually the time to
be in the opposite. It's the time to
just wait to receive whatever it is, you
know, you're waiting for or you're
seeking. Mhm. And so, that's the
practice for me that's been pretty crazy
um opening up you know, I feel like
my spirit and uh self way more is by
kind of those those type of
um thoughts and practices around
you know, giving and receiving. Um
but
receiving more in as far as like, you
know, the feminine side of things to be
more whole.
Yeah. Yeah, I I I like the way you put
it like the like the masculine is kind
of like bracing against the storm and
then there's also this feminine nature
that knows like sometimes it's like, you
know, let that storm just lift you. You
got to like, you know, lift your legs
and let the stream flow you down sort of
thing. Like there is this this push and
pull and it's not always just
like harden up and put armor on and and,
you know, paradoxically there is times
for that, but it it does have to be a
balance. Have you noticed um
you know, as as you have like further
down your path
and gotten more tuned into your
spiritual nature and like kind of
figured out probably what that means for
you
um
spirituality is like such a loaded term
these days, you know. It's like almost
there's so much into it and there's so
many things that are preconceived when
you hear the word spirituality it it can
be disregarding to people who are like,
you know, not into it or something, but
I I kind of see it as something that
whether you use the language or not,
like you have a spiritual aspect of
yourself and and
you don't have to express it on the
surface or whatever, but, you know, it's
your it's your dialogue with the
universe. It's your interaction like
you know,
how you read synchronicities, how you
read coincidences, how you read like,
I'm working on this certain thing and
then this thing happened to come up the
next day. Like, you know, that's pretty
weird. Maybe I should lean into that,
you know. We're always looking for
little signals from the universe from
within that are
guiding us towards a certain direction.
Um, what has been
what have you seen like as you're trying
to as you're like leaning into these
spiritual communities for you
um
as you're developing, as you're like you
said like connecting with more um you
know, men who are kind of on on this
path who maybe 10, 15 years ago they
probably wouldn't use words like
spiritual or maybe they didn't have a
relationship with God, whatever that
means to them again. Um, what are you
seeing? What are the conversations
you're having? Um,
yeah, what what's it like?
Yeah, it's been really weird because
it's like um
it's kind of like a vibrational thing or
something, like the frequency. Because
when [clears throat] I when I change the
way how I think, how I operate, you
know, people might call it changing my
frequency or my vibration or just who I
am. Um
when that changes and it's like um it's
like a reprogramming. And when that
happens, it's weird that it's almost
like
you're a magnet and or a you're you're
you're able to attract
these relationships with these people
um
and connect where you saw this
relationship as this,
you know, previously and then you
connect again over here this later part
of your life.
>> [clears throat]
>> Excuse me.
And then you're like
we just had this crazy you know, like
you're saying synchronicity and we
totally connected about like something
spiritual and I would had no idea this
guy was like that. And then you you're
like this this is cool, you know.
Um [snorts]
and it you know, it
I think we we we briefly talked about it
like through messaging a while back, but
I think it it kind of brings into that
that little part of you know
people think you're one way
because of how they grew up with you or
whatever and then you change and then
you know, we're on this path of maybe
like curating that friend group. Not
like cutting people out, but like you
just you just choose to give energy and
spend time with people that um
really uh resonate with you
and vice versa. Um
I think those those relationships are
kind of what I found that um have kind
of popped up a re- a re- reoccurrence of
these um people that are on the same
path and I'm just like this is weird,
you know, it's just cool. So, you know,
you were like a person
that I've always um since we met like
you're probably like one of the first
people I was like this guy is different,
you know, like
as as I'm like struggling through my own
slop and everything else like I remember
we were going um
like it was like
one of the Lake Shasta trips we were on
and you were like up early running
around like jogging or something and
then you're like meditating Mark our
friend Mark was like yeah he's he does
this every morning or whatever. I'm like
what? That's crazy.
And I was like that's that's awesome,
you know, it's so good to do that. Um
and so and then just seeing like your
podcast and how you evolved
um
and like listening to you um you're just
one of those people that for me it's
like one of those people I want to make
sure um
we have this like thread and we talk
about stuff, you know, whether it might
be a few months at a time but um
you're one of those guys that I feel
like in this case like I'm attracted to
you in that sense um
for this reason um where it's in other
in other parts of my life it's been the
other way where people are like you're
kind of like the beacon, right?
Or people are like
so I heard you talking about this the
other day like overheard you like at
work or something
and like you know
do you really meditate? I'm like
[clears throat]
oh yeah, I do. And like that's so cool.
Like what?
You know, so it's been it's been really
cool seeing how
you're not really losing anything by
just committing to this kind of a
a lifestyle or you know, a way of
thinking. You're
you know, if anything you're you're
gaining everything.
Um
Yeah, we we kind of start to get drawn
firstly thank you for saying that it's
very sweet of you to to observe that and
then communicate that to me. Um
obviously I you know
I love Mark so much. He's He's He's a
good friend of both of ours and
with my friends it's like if if they
vouch [clears throat] for him and they
say they're cool, I'm like cool, they're
cool. And obviously as I feel like we
connected pretty quickly right away.
Man, we just we met on the same page
like regardless of if I was waking up
earlier and going for runs and
meditating and stuff like that. I feel
like you and I vibe pretty quickly right
immediately. So,
um
but you know, it is when I was younger
what I thought was cool was
uh I was just talking about The Wolf of
Wall Street.
Uh like the Jordan Belfort. I remember
like when I was when I was DJing and
like partying every weekend and stuff.
Um
I remember like my visuals would start
out from like the scene where it's just
like a woman's butt cheeks and and then
he like his head comes up above and he
like snorts blow off of her butt cheeks
>> [laughter]
>> and like that was my visuals while I was
DJing, you know, like I thought that was
cool.
And then like, you know, later in life
we have these experiences. Um you know,
I had like these like weird series of
awakenings and then suddenly it's like
what I think is cool is like
like Buddhist monks, you know. And And
like suddenly you're kind of drawn more
towards those things. And I'm thinking
of um
Ra- Ram Dass would say
um I work on myself so that when others
need to come up for air, there I am.
Mhm. That's good.
>> And it is it is so cool it's it's just
that same thing we were talking about
about how
you know,
how you get into like these
self-development things. You're like I
never heard anybody have that
perspective before. It's kind of like a
little bell over here like I got a cone
on and I am this person and I'm going to
do this and I think these things are
dope and I'm, you know, I'm never going
to change. I'm this person and then you
like hear this little bell of like,
"Hey, have you thought about thinking
like this?" And you're like
huh.
That's kind of cool.
You know, and then you could either like
put your head back into your cone or you
can kind of go like, "What is that all
about, you know, over there?" And so
like what a beautiful thing that when we
can follow our own path that we have a
frequency, we have a sound that can be
heard by others. And again, it's not
like we're proselytizing or we're not
trying to be like, "You need to be more
like me." or whatever, but when they do
want to come up for air,
, you know, they can they can
have those conversations with us. And uh
And again, there's no like there's no
like hierarchy with it either. It's
like, "Man, I I don't expect you to be
anything. You don't have to be more like
me. I'm not judging you for whatever you
do, you know, I have my past. I have my
I you know,
my poop stinks too, you know, like
like I'm human just as well." But um
yeah, I'm I'm dry It's It's funny cuz I
notice often you probably have more and
more of these experiences like
I'll be talking with somebody at work.
They'll be working with me for multiple
days. Like we'll get along great, but
you know, I'm not I'm not going to shove
my spiritual stuff or my
self-development stuff down anybody's
throat, you know.
But like suddenly
it comes up in conversation like, "Oh
yeah, you know, I got my meditation
teacher teacher certification." And then
like
I noticed it just happened like 3 weeks
ago. This guy was telling me like, "Oh."
He was like really like attentive to to
me. And I liked him. He's He's a cool
guy.
Um but since I said that and then like I
got a little alone time with him. We're
working or like, you know, running
cables or something. And then he's like,
"Man, I did this meditation actually not
long ago and it was like Dude, it was so
cool." And you could tell he doesn't
know nothing about any of that
He's just not in this lingo. It's not in
this language. It's not like he doesn't
It's not his thing. But then he knew
that like I'd be willing to talk about
it without any judgment and I'd be
excited to talk to him about it. And so
suddenly I have like this whole
conversation about meditation and kind
of like how spirituality is for me. And
you know, it's cool to think that what I
what I love doing, what I am super into,
what I you know, the frequency that I
like to put out
he he can find a thread of maybe
something through it, you know. Like
maybe now Like if he thinks I'm cool, if
he thinks I'm cool, like just how I
thought Jordan Belfort from Wolf of Wall
Street was cool,
he can now have permission to lean more
into maybe like, "Okay, well, there is
actually guys who I think are cool who
are into meditation, and I did have that
one experience. I don't have to write it
off as this one-time happenstance. Maybe
I'm going to try some more meditations,
you know?" And um yeah, it's it's like
I think that's what leadership is, you
know? Like especially as men, like we
stand proudly in our own skin and and we
do our work, and you know, hopefully
people who are
you know, metaphorically shorter than us
at that moment, they can kind of like
look up and go, "Okay, cool. I'm going
to I'm going to walk up the hill towards
my version of that, you know?" We
inspire each other by doing our own
work. Yeah, for sure.
And I [clears throat] think there's a
little bit I mean
I wouldn't say I like I like that men
are shorter than shorter men than us
that metaphorically. Yeah,
metaphorically. Yeah, but it's it's you
know, cuz
it's a growth, right? As if we're all if
we're all like, you know, as as a symbol
like maybe like a tree or something. Um
you know, everyone's just on that
different Everyone's gets planted and
they want to grow at some point or some
people don't, you know? But, you know,
kind of striving for like I want to be
like that tree or, you know, that that
thing. That sequoia is huge, you know?
It's some like obviously some maybe some
spiritual leader or, you know, just some
person that's just really right in a lot
of ways to the way you think, you know?
It's kind of like that example of um
something to strive for, something to
grow towards. Yeah. Yeah,
or else we're just walking around and
following whatever smells the best that
day. Like I said it was earlier, like
with the waffles. Like We have we have
this human body. We have these urges,
whether they be, you know, food or
sexual or or attention or whatever our
thing is. We've all got our things, you
know? And I think if we don't have some
sort of little
uh you know, if we don't have some part
of us that isn't tuning into that some
frequency that makes sense for us
towards a a better good, a higher good,
uh
um
>> [clears throat]
>> you know, some sort of escalation
towards
you know, growth mindset of of of who we
want to be one day, of of who what we
want to accomplish while we're here for
this short amount of time,
uh we'll be just at the whims of
whatever smells good and whatever like,
you know,
like
it's all sold to us, it's all inundated
into our faces all day, every day. It's
what marketing is, it's what our our our
society is and it's just constantly
trying to steal your attention from
hey, smell this. Hey, look at this. Hey,
you know, check out these boobs over
here. You don't want to You want to
think about those. And you're like,
well, yeah, I do think those are cool,
but also like I'm in a committed
relationship and I made a a devotion
over here. And they're like, but these
boobs are cool, you know. And so you got
to have some sort of grounding and like,
no, I I'm in this relationship, you
know. And so we so we don't get
persuaded, you know.
Um
Dude, I I uh
I'm curious, what what is your
meditation been like? Like what what is
your meditation practice? And I also I
will caveat
think of whoever is listening, maybe
they've never really meditated before.
And so I would love to know like when
you kind of started getting into
meditation, what ones did you do? Like
guided YouTube? What what what what's it
What's it been for you?
Uh no, it's
>> [clears throat]
>> actually something It's one of those uh
um
you know, skills I'm I want to get
better at and I'm diving going to dive
going to, you know, dive deeper into it,
like the actual mechanics of it. Um
but like a little quick backstory, you
know, for me, um
I
I grew up in a
in a church [clears throat]
and um it was like a pretty I I think
later on we found out it was like a it
was like I think pretty much a cult. It
was like on Netflix, there was like some
something about it, Some like Christian
cult church.
And then looking back, I'm like,
yeah that's how I I'll check out. Um but
like you know, being in the church,
there was I think there were some kind
of um
some kind of cornerstones laid at that
point. Um just with spirituality. Um and
then I kind of had my and I I I was in
church, you know, probably through
high school, a couple years out of out
of high school.
Um at different stages of that path.
And then [snorts] I just kind of like I
just
I just kind of fell out of favor with it
with um
uh
my thoughts and kind of where I was
going um
with my own spiritual journey and
uh it was more of the religious aspect
than the actual like um the physical um
doctrine of some of the you know, the
ideas of it. Um
but
I kind of got to this point where um
for me
it was actually
it's been for I mean, it's been kind of
fresh, but um
last year was like the the big
turning point for as far as like
meditation goes.
Um and for me meditation um
really started as
um
like moving my body and like stretching.
Like like the the intention of like
connecting back to self.
And I think that's what what really
spurred on um
the the meditative side of it. So like
in the morning, I would um
I would just spend time with myself, get
up earlier, and I would just stretch,
just just like work on my breath. Uh
for me, it really started with
uh
stretching uh in the morning and just
kind of connect reconnecting with my
body. Cuz I I I I just felt myself so
disconnected. Um like we're talking
about kind of the masculine and the
feminine like feminine. Um I was just so
in the
just action action action. I just needed
work work work work work work work.
And I just found myself so disconnected.
Um and it was showing
it was just like showing signs like, you
know, um
kind of like the you know, as within so
without type of type of way of thinking.
Um you think you're a certain way, but
then your life shows you actually how
you are inside, you know, and you're
like, "Oh, this stinks, you know, I I I
stink, you know, I I can't hide it
anymore, you know?" Um
and for me that was like
there was so many things like uh
you know, the partying, the drinking, um
all all the vices for sure. And
so
started with the stretching and just
really kind of like the breath work uh
just like
you know, working on
you know, sending the breath to the
body, sending the breath to the the part
you're trying to stretch and just you
know, kind of like dropping in a little
bit in that in that sense. Then you kind
of like um
I guess you kind of you know, it's like
working out. You sort of like
you know,
memorizing your body's realizing this is
kind of something we're doing.
Um
but then
adding to that after stretching uh for
me it was just like
breath work and um
and then
I just I came back to prayer.
For me.
Um so it was just like
like honest prayer and um
with you know, with
gratitude and um
also being open to like
the energy of
the receiving like we're talking about.
Like Mhm.
the gratitude
but also praying for things and uh not
not like
you want something, but
just asking for you know guidance and
you know
really putting the intention out there
and I think that was kind of the other
thing was the intention of everything
was not
not necessarily for
um
selfish reasons it was more just like
for me to really just connect back with
self and set the intentions of like a
trajectory like a there's a cross in the
roads I was like I I'm just done
pretending I'm living this way I'm
actually going to live this way
and making that decision through
you know like I said connect back with
self and and and meditating that in to
that aspect that's that was kind of how
I found it. Mhm. Yeah brilliant man.
Well
you you probably know this but yoga
defined is is yolk
y o l k like yolk union with with self
union union with the body.
So so I remember when I first got into
yoga
I was saddened by
the fact that it has for one we perceive
it as like what it's a workout thing
like you do it to stretch your body and
and you and you sweat at the gym but
it's actually like this very like
personal spiritual thing
and it's also it also saddens me too.
I still come across like just to use
that as an example like Christians for
example they think that yoga is like
devil stuff like it's like that you're
you're worshipping a deity it's like
what that's what you
like
moving your body and breathing and like
getting out of your mind and connecting
with like what it feels like when you
breathe out right here physically like
that is devil stuff what are you what
are you talking about you know
and it it is like
I think we do get super disembodied
like disembodied in a
metaphorical and a literal sense you
know like when we're living in our mind,
like you said, you kind of have these
illusions of like you almost lie to
yourself in a weird way. I mean, at
least that's kind of how it was for me.
Like but but you can't really lie to
yourself, as it turns out. Like you
could think you can with your mouth, but
like your body knows the truth of
things. And so, yeah, when you align and
you start stretching, you start you
don't even have to like say you're doing
yoga.
Um you just kind of start moving your
body and then suddenly your breath
changes. And then that changes like all
these chemical things in your body.
And that brings you new thoughts. That
brings you I think um
you know, like if
if if we have this this frequency or
this um receiver rather to tune into
frequencies,
I think like, you know, if you're
running from a lion and you're scared
and you think you're going to die and
your your breath is shallow up in your
chest and
you're going to tune into frequency
thoughts of of fear of of
And it makes sense because where, you
know, you got to survive. You need to
It's not the time to be thinking about
like the fact that you're on a giant
rock floating through space and like all
these big old ideas as you're just
trying to survive. Right. So,
when we're disconnected from our body
and our breath, we are in this strange
survival mode. And I think, especially
for like modern dudes,
we're almost locked into that for like
literal years, dude. We wake up and we
go. And then it's like you you know, you
have a drink to fall asleep because
you're trying to go, but your your body
is a body and needs rest. And so, you're
like, all right, let me take an Ambien
or let me like get to sleep so I can
just get through the next day. And then
you wake up and you're all groggy and
there's all You don't have time to
connect with your body and and be
peaceful and all this. You got to
go to work. And so, you know,
it's a
it's a genuine awakening for a lot of
us, I think, when we finally give
ourselves a little bit of time to slow
down and breathe a little bit and
stretch a little bit and like allow
whatever it is that's going on to be
there
without you know attacking it and
pulverizing it on the other side without
and without judging ourselves for being
where we're at cuz you know we we can't
we can't move from where we are not you
know Yeah and I started yoga as well and
that last part is rings true with me
because uh
>> [snorts]
>> I I'm pretty still Yeah even doing it
for a couple months now it's like
I still need to release body's still
tight Yeah You watching people they're
just doing all sorts of crazy stuff
you're like
give me those blocks Yeah yeah
but that's that's the it's a good
example though cuz like watching other
people you're not in their body you
don't have their you don't have their
karma you don't have their um or their
experiences I mean I think more and more
there's more and more books like the if
you've heard of the book the body keeps
the score
um
it there's essentially not just in that
book but I mean kind of in like
the larger even Buddhist contexts
when you sit and meditate like if you go
on like a 10-day Vipassanā retreat for
example where you just you're just
following the breath like it's just this
massively
that's it like those are the
instructions
you find that
your body like suddenly your knee you
know you're 3 hours into this like
you're in a trance state and then you're
like oh my knee got hurt and then you
see your knee is like oh it really hurts
and then it's like you can't think of
anything it's this excruciating pain of
your knee and you're like is it with the
way I'm sitting whatever and like
sometimes what happens is literally
there will be a physical body like
letting go like imagine like if you're
all stressed and then you finally it is
all relieved and it's like oh there's no
problem your shoulders go
>> [sighs]
>> Yeah
There's there's microcosms of that
happening in our bodies and we hold them
with like with our personality with our
armor, with our
you know,
we're physically holding in like in real
life, like in the like in real life,
we're physically clenching, and it
equates to kind of like
our traumas, what happened to us, what
we're holding against. Like I I use this
example, like if I go if I was in your
face and I go, "Boom!" You're going to
you're going to kind of flinch a little
bit. And life is always kind of giving
us little reasons to flinch, especially
when we're like very young, when we're
when we're learning about the world
around us, we're learning how to look
out for those flinches so we can you
know,
guard ourselves against them or prepare
for them. Uh but then as we get older,
it's kind of an act of how can I
through whatever process it is,
release the tension. And And it's not
always meditation and yoga. Like
sometimes it's just like accepting love
from a woman.
And then suddenly your shoulders go
down. And it's like, "Oh,
I don't have to do anything and she
still like accepts me." And your your
shoulders go down 10 ft, you know. And
And
so it's just like um
our body can really be an opening, dude.
Our body can really be a a way in to
releasing tension not of just the
physical body, but tension of
of like the clenching self, you know?
Yeah. Yeah. When
what I've also found with that is for
me, like I've gotten like uh
super crystal girl into this stuff, but
like uh uh I'm like a huge proponent and
um
fan of astrology.
And um
what I've found, like it's it's It may
not be for everyone, but in my case, so
um I'm a Sagittarius. And
Sagittarius rules like the hips. And um
all of my tension
is in my hips. That's where I'm storing
a lot of this energy and a lot a lot of
this like um pent-up, you know, uh
you know, uh maybe trauma or you want to
call it trauma or just, you know,
energy that needs to like release, you
know, so
and
I found that um
to be like super true uh
as far as like movement of body and then
like, you know, what kind of like
dropping in seeing where you're really
tight and it's like, oh, like actually
makes a lot of sense
for me. Um
uh it's that's been a that's been a
really cool uh
you know, part part of the
the path for me and and like the
meditation and the stretching and the
yoga is uh
it's more like for a for it's more like
for me it's more like the program for
life for me uh how it kind of like can
understand things more and like for me
receive symbols and signs is um through
astrology. Um which is, you know,
obviously like yoga it's it's Satan
worship or something, you know.
>> Yeah, yeah.
But it's [clears throat] interesting
because like with with the background uh
real quick um on that um
I still like to read the Bible
um because I think there's there's a lot
of good in it. Um
and there's certain things like you'll
you'll see you'll hear stuff like that,
right? From like pastors and stuff.
Uh
I remember me and my girlfriend we went
to like a a big church to cuz everyone's
like, oh, this is the best church you
got to go. And literally like 30 minutes
in he starts talking crap about
Catholics and and uh you know, astrology
and yoga how it's all like, you know,
you're going to go to hell pretty much.
And we just looked at each other we're
like,
what is this?
>> [laughter]
>> And he's like some
what I hated was crazy like he's just
like this big
like
fat guy on a like a pedestal.
And I'm like, first of all, I don't want
my spiritual leader to be unhealthy.
Sorry.
You can call me racist, but this doesn't
seem like you got it, you know, and then
you're just like singling everybody out.
But
I like to look at those kind of things
and
I guess it's kind of like a truth seeker
thing in me, but
it doesn't say in the Bible that, you
know, like yoga or especially astrology,
that's that's a big one people people
use, is a um
you know, it's like it's from Satan or
something.
In fact, like in Genesis, it actually
says like, you know, God created the
basically the stars for symbols and
signs. Like
There you go.
You know, he's like giving you
astrology.
>> He's basically saying, "Hey, I'm giving
you the the road map
above your head. It's right there. And
that's how, you know, if you ever have
any questions, it's right there." And
you look in you know, ancient history,
that's kind of like how everyone kind of
like started with uh you know, figuring
stuff out with is it's some form of
astrology and science and
and then later in the Bible, it's like
the the the end of the book
um of like towards the end of the Bible,
uh I believe Jesus talks about it. Don't
quote me on that, but
he warns
about
astrol- astrologers, basically. So, a
lot of people take that context.
But, they leave the rest of what he's
saying out. He also warns against
lawyers, judges, uh priests.
Basically, he's saying like, "Don't give
up your soul and your energy to people
that can influence you." Cuz people that
know astrology really well,
like you go to psychic or some
astrologer, like, "Give me a future
reading." Like, you're you're opening up
that field and you're letting letting
them into like basically your blueprint.
So,
the Bible's warning against that.
You know, like, "Hey, don't don't let
yourself get into these positions where
these people can influence you and
potentially control you."
Yeah. So, that's been it's been really
cool for me. At least that part of it.
This path is like all the things we're
talking about.
Kind of getting getting a a different
lens on a lot of these things that, you
know, people are like, you know, the
Bible thumpers are like, it's this and
it's that and then you it's you're like
going to hell.
It's like you just
This book is so much deeper than that
and it's not even just this book. Like
there's this The teachings are are are
way deeper than just the words on the
page. Yeah. Yeah, I mean, dude,
discernment is such an important factor.
Like you could you could be very open.
You could be 100% open to like really
listen like, okay, so you think that
So, it says this in the Bible and your
interpretation of it is this and here's
how it works in your life. Like you
could be open 100%. Like you could
listen to whatever someone even if
you're like as they're telling you what
their what their belief about the
universe or God or whatever it is.
Even if you're like, man, I don't think
that's true whatever. But like you can
remain open to it and still hear it and
still listen to it. But then you have
discernment. You have Well, what do I
think about it? Because we individually
I I never really jive too well with
like that dude has to be my connection
to God. Like it all has to run through
that dude cuz he like cuz he
has like his name is on a some piece of
paper and he owns this building and like
what? But like when I read it, I read
that exact same thing and I didn't see
it the way that he saw it, you know?
Mhm. And so I
I think it's like
it is nice to trust someone. It is nice
to trust that like, hey man, that guy
studies the Bible. That guy studies the
stuff and he says it's this way. So,
like I should listen to him. Sure.
But again, you run it through your own
discernment. You have your own like
faucet connected to God itself. We each
do. And so I think that like if if you
hear something you're I don't know if
that really makes much sense to me.
That's okay. That's good. Like it's not
like it's not like you're going against
the Christian church cuz you're like,
well, I don't know if I really dig that
part of it. Let me come over here on
YouTube. Let me come over here to these
books and kind of like do some more
research. Like you, you know, you're
like you know, you hear these things
like
if you're into astrology, you're you're
demon worship or whatever. And you're
like, well, that doesn't that doesn't
really jive with what I've learned. And
then you go and you know, dive deeper
into astrology and you're like, well,
this for me for my frequency for the way
that I understand this language from the
universe, it's kind of makes sense to
me, you know? And
I I don't want to bash on Christians by
any means and obviously it's not all
Christians, but I do find it often with
Christianity, they like slam doors on
everybody else cuz they think that
everyone else is like worshiping a
deity. Like they're like, oh, Hinduism,
that's your worshiping or Buddhism,
you're worshiping the Buddha. It's like,
what? Have you like read any of Like
that's not what anybody thinks they're
doing. Like we're not
it
people use like one little scripture
and they'll say like
you know, the only way to come through
God is through me.
And they think that means like the small
self Jesus, like the like the name he
was given at birth.
You know? And it's like, no, he's saying
through me as in like God as in through
you that also has this flow to the
universe. Yeah, like as as Jesus is the
the physical representation of all of us
on Earth. The physical The physical God.
So, he's saying the only way to God is
through yourself.
Yeah, yeah. And and not
and not just the small self, like the
the capital S self, you know? You know?
And it's again
I mean, we're we're all everybody's on
their own path. They have to understand.
Like, you know, cuz there's people who
they can read like
75 astrology books and still go, this
doesn't make sense to me, you know? But
I think I'm always really loving to
encourage people to like find what your
spiritual path is. Like what language
makes sense to you? Like we all speak
different languages. We all hear
different things. Like it doesn't all
have to be just this one exact thing.
Like some days, bro, like when I'm
trying to like read through scriptures
or like I've been doing a um
a discipleship with some with some
friends, like I'm trying to I've always
been very much like the Eastern stuff,
the
you know, uh if you've heard of Advaita
Vedanta, that's like kind of my favorite
like um
wisdom lineage. It's like pre-Hinduism
and stuff. Uh that's has always made the
most sense to me.
But I know there's some great great
stuff in in the Bible, in Jesus, in
Christianity, and all that stuff. And a
lot of days I find like, "Oh man, that
that verse hits. That's exactly what I'm
going through. That works perfectly."
You know, I I often pray to Jesus. I,
you know,
I'm working on my relationship with him
cuz it's always you we can have our
personal relationship with with Jesus
and with our with our own spirituality.
Um but it's like
I I I'm not going to shut any of it
down, you know? Like I want to it's it's
not either or. And so sometimes I just
feel like a lot of people get really
caught up with, "Well, if you believe in
Jesus, it's not possible to believe in
this other stuff."
Yeah. And it's like what that's a
strange door to slam that doesn't need
slammed. Like we could all communicate.
If for me, I start talking to a
Christian or I start talking to a
Buddhist or whatever, and within a few
seconds I'm like, "Oh, I know what
you're talking about." Like I like, "Oh,
we're talking about the same thing."
Maybe we use a different maybe we wear
different color shirts while we're
wearing it, but like we're kind of
talking about the same thing. And you
meet there and you connect with them
through there.
Yeah, it's cool you mentioned that. Um
because I got this um
this buddy at work, he uh his name's
Aziz, which is he he's a sadge and uh
for me in astrology, Zeus is like you
know, the
the the ruler of Jupiter.
Um
so
I don't that was kind of cool his name
followed his his like his sign, but he's
um he's Muslim and he's super cool guy.
He's he's pretty young. He's a sales guy
at my work and um
you know, we started like talking about
like prayer and everything like that and
um
I was just like, gosh, you know, I just
want to I want to experience it.
I don't know if this is going to be cool
or not. I was like but I was like, hey
Zeus, you know, can
um
can I go with you to you know, to mosque
to prayer?
And he was just like
you you want to you want to come? I was
like, yeah, I want to I want to I want
to check it out. I want to see see what
see what's going on.
And he's like, oh my he's like, yeah,
this Friday. Friday I go Friday at noon.
I was like, all right. And then Friday
came and he never like texted me like
we're at we're working the same
dealership and then um
I was like, hey, we leaving? He's like,
wait, you're serious? You're serious?
And I was like, yeah, let's go.
>> [laughter]
>> I had to wait like another week. He's
like, I felt so bad, dude. I I thought
you were just joking. I was like, no,
I'm serious. He's like, okay, okay. And
so the next Friday like we were like we
we saddle up and we went and um
it was crazy like this little building
in Beaverton and then like
it's just everyone all these guys and
people show up
and everyone's parking everyone's like
getting in line. We had to go in line.
We had to walk we had to wash our feet
and our hands a certain way and then
like you know, he's showing me
everything
go inside to like the big prayer room
and there's rugs everywhere and
everyone's
standing and
and praying and then there there's a
little sermon.
Of course, I couldn't understand any of
it, but you know, I I could I could tell
by the energy and the vibes kind of what
was going on.
Um
And so it was really cool
seeing
kind of like you're saying like the the
the the similarities between um
just the energy of like, you know, maybe
you know, like you call it Christ
consciousness or or you know, whatever
it is.
Uh where
there's something similar
All these religions are tied to the same
anchors that we all we all dislike, you
know, the the rigidity, the the
the uh
you're not going somewhere because of
it, you know, your soul's screwed, you
know.
Um
but seeing how they operate and how, you
know,
they do their their their church
basically is was really really cool.
Um and it kind of made me sad that
there's so much like tradition and like
honor in how they pray and how they
worship
and how that's just not
like normal Christianity.
It's more like the more obscure and hip
you are in like modern Christianity is
like
that's how that's how people are going
to come into your church. You know,
where I think I was reading somewhere
like
Catholicism has like a massive shift in
like young people starting to join
because of the rigidity. That's their
that was the article's like their thing
is like
their people are just going to get
burned out on all the crazy
crazy worship and all the coffee and all
the cool things to come into the, you
know, and it's just like you come in,
you know what you're going to get and
there's certain things that you're just
going to do
and for whatever reason that seems like
a more
you know, good thing for those kind of
people
that would want that.
But
I I just
again kind of opening yourself up, kind
of what we kind of been talking about,
but the whole like
uh
attracting things and I would have never
thought to
ask those, you know, ask him to go see
that, but I was on I'm I'm on that vibe
and I'm that's that's part of my path
and
and seeing it's a this whole another
world. Then like, you know, he gave me a
a Quran and like a little a little
little like Seventh-day Adventist book
like this is why you should join. So,
it's it's fine, but like also reading
that I'm like, "Oh, this is super
interesting." Like,
all right. All right.
Yeah, dude. Wow, that's so cool. That's
like what a what a beautiful experience.
Like, what a
I mean
because it could be religion itself and
not all religion, but as a blanket
statement, it can really be a walled
garden.
Like, if you
if you don't say the right words out the
door and vow to do these things and
you're not allowed to be a part of our a
part of our thing. Like, if you don't
like, you know, like you were saying
earlier like you go you go to a church
and then, you know, 30 minutes in there
they're talking about all these other
all the Hindus are going to hell and all
the Buddhists are going to hell and all
the it's you either do our way or or the
highway, you know, and
I think we got to more
more so be open to
uh what our personal life is handing us.
Like, dude, you had that experience. You
had a co-worker who you got along with
on that level. You guys had this
frequency together. You felt open enough
to be vulnerable enough to really like
again, maybe like you're
you're open to your more feminine side
of like, "Hey, I want to that does sound
interesting, man. Let Let me check that
out. Like, it seems like it works for
you. I've heard cool things about it,
whatever. Let me go like really really
give in, you know." And you were able to
like I mean, you did the thing. You took
you took your shoes off and you washed
your hands and you washed your feet.
Like, that's you really gave gave it a
try and I feel like
um
What What is the What is the like the
unforgivable sin is like um
uh
like basically
What is like the one thing in
Christianity? I It's like
to create to
blasphemy or something like that? Like,
to to not accept God or something like
that? Does that ring any bells?
Yeah.
>> [sighs]
>> Like like not
I think basically like not being open to
it is is my interpretation.
>> a total rejection of God would probably
>> Like of course that cuts you off from
God. And so you don't have to
pre-conceive what God's shape already
is,
but be open to it however it may be
presenting itself, I guess, is what I'm
trying to say.
Yeah. And and like there's there's a lot
of beauty in that, man. There's a lot of
community in that.
>> And it um
It's interesting, too, back to astrology
real quick, but Please.
>> they worship on Friday, which is ruled
by Venus.
And so and a lot of a lot of um a lot of
their
their uh religion is
if you look at it, it's a really it's
there's a lot of Venusian aspects to the
religion, so it's very interesting. And
then you see somewhere like uh
like Jew Jewish people worship on um
Saturday, which is Saturn's day, which
is Saturn, Satan.
I'm not saying I'm just saying that's
that's
But you know, and and the depending on
what you know, what sect of Judaism it
is, like, you know, it's if they're
pretty open to like, yeah, no, it's
Saturn. That's you know, it's that's
that's who we pray to.
Um
And then, you know, Christianity and
some of these other religions are on a
Sunday, which is, you know,
sun, son of God, Jesus, you know, sun
worship.
Um so it's kind of interesting. Yeah.
>> That was it was super like interesting
for me like like being there and like,
oh, this is cool, like and just like
kind of like putting these little things
together in my head, you know. Yeah. Um
Do you Do you think like thinking back
say just as a rough number like 7, 8
years ago, do you think you would be
open to that same experience?
I don't know.
I've always been super curious with
anything like
esoteric or faith-based, anything like
that.
Um
I would put a question mark cuz I don't
know. I don't know.
I may not have I may not I I may not.
Maybe presented in the right way at the
right time or something perhaps or Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
Um
Well, cuz I
I mean
a theme that we're both definitely
seeing I mean I think everybody is
seeing is like dude
like you said by the masses in some way
a lot of people young people even people
who they had a religious background when
they were younger
more and more people are looking for
spirituality more like the churches are
the churches are packed these days,
dude. Like
whatever denomination you want to call
it the churches are packed like more you
know I I was just listening this morning
the
I don't know if you've seen there's like
some Tibetan monks that live in Dallas.
They've just done a walk
on foot to Washington D.C. to kind of
like like they want to raise awareness
and and and talk about peace and and
like they went to the the monument and
they you know spoke at a podium and
there's just thousands of people there
and there's all these there's people
following with with videos. It's been
like a really cool thing to see on on
social media but
um
I think we're seeing like
at the same time there's all this
turmoil. I mean what we're talking at a
time where like these Epstein files have
just been been released and there's all
this like as much as we see this
this intense evil it's almost like
like everything collectively is being
brought to the surface and it leads us
is like as much as there's more fear
there's also this like well, we're going
to connect back to ourselves and we're
going to like find ways to build our
communities and we're noticing and not
ignoring and not like numbing with
alcohol every night of like I need I
need something bigger than myself to
like think about because every day I'm
getting doom and gloom fed to my phone
fed to my face fed to the TV. It's all
on newspapers. It's it's
it's some some people it's all they
freaking talk about is like what the
news is telling them to be angry about.
But at the same time it seems like we're
seeing so many people
get in touch with their more spiritual
side. Like like I said, I I feel like I
have more and more conversations daily
of people who
Hey, so you're you're in that meditation
stuff. Tell me, you know, tell me about
that. Like, you know, more people are
inquisitive in their in their own ways.
Um
Are you seeing that? Like as obviously,
you know, you're tuning your frequency
into it so it's just more visible to you
anyway, but do you find that like more
of your friends, more people around you
are kind of like making it a little more
okay to like, "Hey, let's go to church.
Let's let's talk about God. Let's pray."
Like praying is like I said, like what
we make cool. Praying is cool, man. Are
you seeing more of this?
Yeah. Um
it's been crazy, you know, kind of to
your point. I I think so people are just
over
overexposed. And I think people are just
getting burned out. Literally burned
out. Their brains are just like, "No, I
I can't do it." Bro, yeah. This isn't
it. Yeah. Maybe maybe that's it. So
let's go try religion or, you know,
whatever the the um spirituality thing
is. Yeah.
So I totally agree with you. Um yeah,
and it it seems like
in my life, you know, there's been quite
a few interactions with people that are
um
especially you know, even at my work,
there's been a couple instances where
people have uh
I thought they were one way or thought
they maybe thought one way of me, you
know, like I just knew that this person
probably was like
you know, that. Like maybe they're like
super super left or super right or
whatever it is, you know. And then like
you start
realizing that like you're you're
interacting more
and they're interacting more cuz they're
you know, they're curious about
something. They don't quite know what it
is. And then they start like asking
little questions or this and that. And
then
and then it's like this full-blown like
Dude, let me know like what's going on
with this like this thing is this
like you know is this a conspiracy or
something like like I'm the conspiracy
guy but I'm just like no I just have a
different idea of what's going on
because what I think you know.
But then it goes into like cuz they know
people just know the way you operate or
they or they maybe they don't and they
just they're just attracted to you know
whatever that frequency you're you know
resonating at. Um
Sometimes it's just been like me just
like picking up the phone and talking to
somebody I haven't talked to for a while
not because I wanted to like
preach or something weird but like then
you realize that this phone call was
actually
meant to happen. Mhm. Cuz then you
realize like you have this phone call
like what's up dude I haven't talked to
you for a while and it's just like
boom this crazy thing happens and you're
just like whoa you
Dude, that's crazy like you're you
changed like you your life is and then
we like completely um
you know connect on a even a deeper
level
you know
That for me has been really cool.
Yeah, dude. Yeah, like
like I really get into
I really get into like synchronicities
and and things like that um
as much as they can get like very weird
in a lot of ways sometimes I
I I think I've gotten more and more as
I've like
deepened my spiritual
whatever.
I find like synchronicities to almost be
in coincidences to almost be not as
shocking anymore. It's just like yeah of
course it's that of course God is
speaking to me through this person. Of
course I was of course I was put in this
hallway. Of course my plane was delayed
so I could sit next to that lady cuz she
was going through a very horrible time
and had a long conversation with her.
You know
and not not to
self grandiose myself being like the one
who who's helping her. I'm I'm not
saying that, but like
it it it's almost
Alan Watts who would would call it like
a cosmic giggle.
You know, it's like the universe going
like, "Hey, man.
Like you might you might think you're
all in control or you you could plot
this all out, but like if you just
just rest into your life
and you follow those little natural
intuitions. They're not even like, "I'm
going to call this guy to talk to him
about spirituality." You're like, "Man,
I'm talk to Dave for a while.
Let's see how he's doing." You ring him
up and you end up having like this
this rekindling that's that's exactly
what you needed, exactly what he needed,
you know, as Ram I'm sure Ram Dass says,
"We're all walking each other home." Uh
I find a way to insert that into every
podcast that I've ever done, I feel
like. Um but it just uh it's true, man.
I think uh
Yeah, the world of sync Have you read
Have you read the book The Celestine
Prophecy?
No. Holy dude. You got to It's so
So it's actually for free on YouTube. Uh
I think it's a legal rip, but it's still
on there. So you could read
>> [laughter]
>> the audiobook I really enjoy because um
I love listening to books while I'm
while I'm walking. Um you might you
might enjoy like while you're out there
hunting and searching for rocks. Like
maybe plug this thing in. The Celestine
Prophecy. It may It may blow your mind
if you're into synchronicities and and
these sorts of things, but um For sure.
It It explains it with a story.
It is a bit of It's It's of course a a
fiction.
It's like this guy looking for these
like secret manuscripts, whatever. But
like reading between the lines of what's
going on in that story is very much akin
to coincidences in in synchronicities in
in those sorts of things. And I just
feel that
the universe is always kind of trying to
give you signals or like your higher
self is or God or whatever. And um
there's moments where when we follow it,
right afterwards we go,
Dude, that
that
Life is crazy. And I'm glad that I
followed that intuition, you know? Yeah.
And I don't know they really start to
add up and it's almost like the the
the inner narrator that judges ourselves
that we all have just being humans. It's
almost like that voice just goes all
right, I'll kind of shut up a little bit
and you'll just start kind of acting
from these more intuitive things. I feel
like synchronicities are
proof of our intuitive voice within in a
lot of ways.
>> Yeah. You know?
I totally agree. It's
It's funny you say that. Um
So I I had this thing so it's like it
was like a selfish thing, right? I I
just I want a new car. I wanted a newer
car. And I really wanted a a Porsche
Cayenne diesel. It's kind of like this
this unique car that was only made for a
couple of years. Yeah,
kind of like really good gas mileage. If
anyone knows me, I have like
my my fleet is just trucks that get like
12 miles a gallon. I drive like 50 miles
a day so it costs a lot of money to just
get to work. And so I was like I just
need something comfortable, cool and you
know, this is I just feel like this is
this is what I want. This is this is the
car. So just like praying about it and I
was like, you know, hey, you know, show
me the you know, show me the right one.
You know, if it comes to me, great. And
I would be searching around searching
around.
And uh
I found one and it was in like Florida.
Which is like I was like, man, it's far.
But it's like the perfect one, you know,
perfect color, it's like a cool spec.
It's like white with red interior, super
cool, low lower miles, really good
service history, like
this is definitely one.
And so I I hit him up. This lady owned
it and she Yeah, I still got it. I was
like, great. Here's the deal. It's kind
of weird, but uh I'm in Oregon.
She's like, oh my gosh. She's like, did
I post it in the wrong state? I was
like, no.
She's like, oh, we're from Oregon. We
just moved down here a few years ago. I
was like, whoa. So then I'm like, stuff
already been I was like, "Oh, this is
definitely the one, you know?"
And [snorts] so, we should get like
she's super cool. We're like we're
hitting it off. Um they're like a
military family and they're um they're
moving and I'm like trying to get this
car before they move and I I'm just
again, action action action action.
And it's not working. I would have to do
so so many hoops to get this car.
And she's like, "You know what? Um she's
like because we agreed on a price. She's
like, "If I don't sell it by the end of
the year, um
I'll I'll hit you up."
Well, cuz we're moving to California. I
was like, "Oh."
Well, yeah. That's way I can I can do
that in a weekend. I can come pick it
up. I don't worry about shipping or
anything. Um she's like, "Yeah, so if I
have it, I'll just hit you up." I was
like, "Okay, cool." So, that couple it
was like, you know, a week and a half
into January. I texted her. She's like,
"Yeah, we just we know we're living in a
hotel right now waiting for our our our
house to kind of get pop up." And she's
like, "And we're kind of we can't need
the car, but she's like, "I'll I'll hit
you up when I want to sell it." I was
like, "Cool."
Then like a week or two passes and she
hits me up. She's like, "Hey, ready to
sell the car?" I was like, "Great. Let's
do this." You know, like I was like,
"Yeah, I'm so excited." I was like I I
was like, "I just need like a couple
days to get go to my bank cuz I had to
cancel my like approval and everything
cuz it was too long. Sure. And then
she's like, "Cool. Yeah."
I got approved and everything. I was
going to get this car and I was going to
I was like, "I'm going to
drive down next weekend, pick it up."
Literally the next morning she texts me.
And she's like, "Hey Tim, just let you
know, uh we were out last night and some
guy said he wanted to buy our car for
like a thousand dollars more." And she's
like, "So, I think we're just going to
sell it to him." I'm just like,
like
Yeah.
>> What's going on? Like what what's I'm
like, "God, what's going on? What are
you doing?"
>> Yeah. You know, I'm like I'm just
literally I was like, "No way." "No way.
That's my car."
>> Yeah. And
I know I I texted her and I was I was
upset. And I was just like, "Hey, you
know, like technically I was like, yeah,
I mean cuz she was in real estate. I was
like,
you understand this, like we
we agreed on a price
and you're like, yep, come get it. Like
it's it's it's like a verbal con- it's
like a verbal contract and it's written
in text. Like I'm I'm not saying you
have to sell me the car, but I'm saying
like, I'd like you to
to like to come like fighting this
thing, you know?
And then the feeling was like, just let
it go. I'm like, no,
I can't can't let it go.
And
it was like a week passed and I was just
I was just pissed, you know, I was just
like,
my girlfriend's like, are you going to
text her back?
And so I was like, the car's still for
sale on Facebook, so obviously it didn't
sell.
And but it's it's already weird now cuz
like the the relationship kind of
soured, obviously, on my end. So I was
just like, this person this person's
whack. And
and then like I was working and then
like uh
someone trades in this like little
GLA Mercedes GLA, so like a little a
little like hatchback, all-wheel drive,
gets like really good gas mileage.
It has like she ordered it brand new
2015.
So it's it's like 10 years old, but she
just bought a new one.
And it potentially had like this big
issue with it, but she was like, I just
don't want to deal with it. You know,
I'm just going to trade it in.
And I end up buying it for really cheap
and I fixed it myself. And it's this
great little car.
And it's God just like it's literally
everything I wanted just packaged
differently. Yeah. Cuz I was like, I
really want a good good gas mileage.
This thing gets like 32 miles a gallon.
I'm like,
all right. You know, this is the this is
the thing.
It doesn't always show up as like it has
to be these this God has to be this Mhm.
and it has to look like this and I want
this and this and this cuz we often I
often find myself praying for that. I'm
not sure people do, too.
>> Yes. Yeah. But, you know, finding that
that God's like, no, dude, I got you."
You want something and I'm going to
provide for you and this is this is what
you're going to get and you're going to
it's actually going to be better cuz
you're going to save money. It actually
costs way less. You don't need to I paid
for it cash. I didn't need to take a
loan out, you know? It's like
it all worked out. But the fight, you
know, like I was like, "Oh,
I asked, you provided, this is it, we're
good." And then she's just like, "Mm,
no. I don't want to sell you the car."
I'm like, "What?" Yeah. I That was I I
thought it was supposed to be this way.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh my my friend Blake said
uh
he he restated in some way like uh
when we get mad like that, it's like
well, if I were God, it wouldn't be this
way, Yeah. It's like a tantrum, you
know? You're just like, Yeah. Yeah. But
it's
>> Bro, I mean I think there is a constant
series of that old saying, man plans,
God laughs. You know?
And it's it's you got to keep like
unwinding.
I mean like what if what if you, you
know, you were pissed cuz that person
like, you know, they had a deal. We want
to
I get the world we live in, but like I
want to believe in a world where, you
know, you you shake a hand, you look a
man in his eye, and you you going to
trust his word, you know? Like I I get
that we don't necessarily all the way up
live in that world, but I'm going to
believe as if we do. Like I'm going to
I'm going to trust a man on his word,
you know?
But
I Yeah, I I I don't know. We
we sometimes if you were to stay mad in
that situation
and you're like, "Well, I guess I'm not
getting a car then. I'm not I
don't even want a car anymore." or
whatever. Like if if you just kept that
anger and you didn't like be open to
that lady who came in or nice to her or
whatever, you wouldn't be open to that
opportunity. So, there's almost like a
balance of when we do have those
inevitable frustrating moments where
we're like, "Dude, what's up, man? I I
prayed for this and it seemed like you
were giving it all to me and then you
just swept it out from under me." Like
the answer is not to go, "Well, well,
eff you then. I ain't I ain't praying
for anything else ever again cuz I'm not
getting my hopes up, you know?
The answer is kind of like
uh I use this term uh
shelf life, like the shelf life of
negative emotions. Like at some point we
got to like go, you know what? Okay. You
know what? You got to the point where
you're like, okay, I guess that one
wasn't meant to be. And then suddenly
this new opportunity that's even better
than before comes about, you know? Yeah.
And I I like I like the best part, I
guess the the the
the part where God's like, this is what
you're going to learn, is the fact that
>> [clears throat]
>> it's still for sale.
>> [laughter]
>> I I had my my buddy Dylan like like
messenger. Oh, it's a way. And I was
like, hey, can you just see if this car
is still for sale? And he like messaged
me like, yeah, she said she's still
available. I was like,
yeah. Man, so so sometimes you wonder
like
when we're all kind of like listening to
these certain frequencies, like when she
was out and about and she listened to
that person who who was like,
uh hey, I'll give you some more money.
You know, she listened to that. Maybe
that in a way kind of like takes her out
of the frequency that you were
connecting with her on in a way, you
know what I mean? This is uh for sure.
She was focused on
the money aspect, which
I mean, if if she just would have said,
I wanted this amount, we wouldn't had
this issue. But we agreed on that.
And
>> Yeah.
you you gave gave it up for a random guy
that didn't even buy the car.
Yeah, obviously.
Yeah, it's it's it's like this take the
money thing. I think it's um
I I don't remember the specifics, but
Dave Chappelle, the comedian,
like a lot of his big uh after he had
done uh the Chappelle Show, there was
basically like this giant like buyout
available or
he would essentially he would he was
offered insane amounts of money, but he
would kind of have to like go against
his morals and he'd have to like give up
his art and he'd have to
have to like look up the exacts, but
essentially it was like
he chose what he knows is right versus
millions of dollars.
Yeah. And then you look at like I mean
now he's
really kind of like
maybe the number one comedian in the
world in some aspects. You're like, you
know, top five or something. Yeah. Um
and that's kind of like that's a lot of
his story now. That's like his like is
part of his legend is like, "Oh, Dave
Chappelle turned down the money."
And there's almost little instances in
all of our life where we know
something's good and then there's
there's still these opportunities. It's
funny in that self-same prophecies
there's all these
in that book there's almost those things
that happen. Like there's little
like they'll be talking about, you know,
some God connection, some spiritual
thing. They're talking about getting
these manuscripts in the book. And then
over in the corner at another table
there's someone like getting angry.
There's someone like there's like an
opportunity for to act a different way.
It's almost like you're old when you're
breaking patterns of old patterns of
like physical holding on of who you used
to be who you think yourself is to be
uh as like a solid state it will like
rattle. It'll go, "Hey, man, are you
sure you don't want to go back to your
old ways?" It's like you're like, "Oh,
I'm I'm in a committed relationship now
and it's beautiful." And then like the
hottest ex you've ever been with sends
you a text and she's like, "Hey, I've
been thinking about you." And you're
like, "Well, you treated me like total
shit." But then you have these
animalistic sides of you where you where
you go, you know, I mean man, she was
super hot and and whatever. And then
suddenly you start listening to like
just these like quick, you know,
pleasure-seeking things versus
like a a smoother, more calm frequency,
you know? Uh it's it's almost like yeah,
like
old patterns I think right before
they're about to break
they kind of holler in a way, you know?
>> then your your ego is like, "Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Yeah." Yeah. You know, this is
safety. This is what what we used to
>> That's familiar. I like that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. What are we doing? We're
going to jump off of the to the unknown?
Mhm. You know, and definitely I'm a
proponent of uh
yeah, death.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah, have many deaths as you can,
you know. Yeah. Uh in in the Eleusinian
Mysteries, uh there's this book uh
uh it's this secret history.
God, what's it called? Brian Muraresku.
The secret history of the religion with
no name or something along those lines.
But, he has this line in there um that
he found in some scripture and it was,
"If you die before you die, when you
die, you will not die."
Uh and it's like it is this constant
like how can you surrender to your ego
and be new every day, you know? And it
and it almost like dissipates your your
overall fear of death itself of like the
physical just leaving this body, you
know? Uh you constantly try to hold on
to this thing that's like, "I want it to
stay like this and I want to have this
perfect thing and when I have this this
perfect living room set up, everything's
going to be great." And it's like what
it's all it's all fickle, you know? It's
all
um
it's all fluid. Like none of this lasts.
Like you can't stay the same. You're not
supposed to stay the same. Like what if
a seed was like, "I'm not breaking open.
I don't want to become a freaking tree,
dude. I don't want to be I I don't want
you know an acorn's going to be like,
'I'm I want to stay an acorn forever.
I'm familiar with acorn.
I don't want to break open into an acorn
tree. That seems I don't know about
that. I'm comfortable with this acorn,
you know?'" We got to continuously like
die to ourself in a sense.
>> Mhm. Yeah.
Yeah, that's been that's been a huge
part of uh
you know, the it's it's another one of
those things that you you know, it's a
your little toolbox, you know, for for
spirituality and you know, whatever path
you're on.
Um
that part of it, you know, the ego death
and
but rebirth and then there's the trust
um kind of like the trust fall of
yourself, um trust fall to you know,
just this this realm we live in.
Um
and just you know that
um
you're creating just a whole new ripple
when you land. And it's it's it's like a
whole new version of yourself, and it's
just a whole new timeline.
That's kind of the thing that I've
started to really really believe in and
kind of like re-
replay in my mind when things are just
I'm fighting something and I'm just
like,
you know, what's
I'm actually more curious about if I
don't do this, like what happens, you
know, and and just go for it.
Um
so that's been pretty cool. Yeah, what
Yeah, what's the invitation here, you
know?
And the more we can notice when we are
caught up in that, like
I want us to stay this way, and go, you
know what?
I got to just surrender.
Mhm.
Yeah.
>> More doors open. Exactly. Yeah. Terence
McKenna says,
another one that I say all the time,
nature loves courage.
Uh you you you jump off of the cliff
it it into the abyss
and you realize it's a feathery bed.
You know? Mhm. And life is continually
that. And it should be.
Um
>> all that
Yeah, can I just ask real quick what uh
how are you doing on time? Are you good?
Am I keeping you from going to work? No,
I got No, I got I got nothing. Nothing
today. Okay, good.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah, we could do like uh I don't
know, like 15 more minutes or something
if you'd like.
Yeah. Cool.
I should I should probably go to work
eventually.
Yeah.
Are you Do you work every day?
Uh How's that work?
It depends on what's what's going on.
Yeah, kind of. Like like today, um
it is We actually went through a time
change last night. It's it's super
weird. Like at 3:00 in the morning, cuz
I'm now in the Dominican Republic, we
went forward in time. So, like
like my phone says it's 11:30, but I
think that like the ship app says that
it's 12:30. It's very confusing. Um but
uh so, it's kind of in waves. It
sometimes it's crazy busy, sometimes
it's uh like I have a couple days where
it's
I'm kind of on call the whole time and
we're just moving 16 hours a day
back-to-back with little sleep. And then
we have other days where
we're like if there's no fires, we don't
have to respond anything. There's some
days where we're at port where we get
like, you know, half the crew goes for 6
hours and they go like have some drinks
and and go to restaurants and walk
around. So, it's an ebb and flow. It's a
It's a lot of work. It's a lot of like
staying on call, but there's there's
plenty of of break time.
Why did you uh
I mean, it's it's it's crazy to me, but
like what what what what sparked this?
Like you want to wanted to work on a
cruise ship. It sounds It sounds amazing
in some in some ways. Yeah, it's uh was
interesting cuz I'm really not a cruise
ship guy. Like I'm not
just the the energetics of things, the
um like if you're if you're
I'm very into my like individuality. I
want to do things my own I want to eat
what I want when I want. I want to um
I don't know. It's constricting being on
like a, you know, like we're kind of
heard hearded as cows. Like you need to
be here and you're not allowed to do
this and there's all these things that
are like or just a little constricting
for me. But,
it it it was an opportunity for work. Um
Funny enough, a little note on
reputation. Uh when I was 15, I got into
live events. I did an internship. The
lighting director for that show,
uh
I I was friends with him immediately.
He's really cool guy. Um I worked hard.
I asked him a lot of questions. He had
to stay up till like 3:00 in the morning
one of the nights and I was like, I know
nothing about lights, but I want to help
you. And so, I stayed up with him and we
I helped him. Bonded with him. Still one
of my good friends.
Um
Stayed in touch with him and like his
whole crew kind of through social media
just here and there. We all work in
events, you know, comment on each
other's stuff every, you know, a couple
times a year whatever.
Um
And then, I was just working in
I was working in Dallas a while back ago
and I had brought up a crew from Austin
and I didn't even realize it, but the
the the lighting director that I was
just talking about, he now has a company
and he was the company in charge of the
people who hired our labor company
from Austin. So, essentially, I'm like
loading in, like bringing stuff in, I
see across the room, like, "Justin?"
Dude, what's up? And so, we we we
rekindle um
we've worked with a lot of the same
people. I have a great reputation in
that in that scene, like everybody knows
my work ethic and what I'm capable of
and you know, people see what I do on
social media and stuff and so, they kind
of know a little bit about me and stuff.
And so, it's immediately like,
"Well, wait, dude, like, what are you
what are you doing the rest of the
week?"
And I was like, "Well, I got to bring
these bring my crew back to Austin, but
I don't have I have some days off."
They're like, "Drop them off, come back
up, work the rest of it." Um they gave
me a new role, breakout operator, um
running like breakout rooms, like little
little mics and like small screens for
like, you know, 40 to 80 people, stuff
like that. Um
so, I have so, reputation long-term from
when I was 15 to now 34, like, I kept
that reputation of just hard work ethic
and like, being someone who's like,
"Yeah, let's bring that guy on." Um so,
they had me come up, I worked the rest
of the week.
Prove yourself there and they're like,
"Well,
we're we're doing these cruises, like,
what are you doing during these dates?"
And then so, they asked me to come on
the cruise.
Yeah, so,
just like opportunity, I suppose, you
know, um I've been I do a lot of stuff
at events. I travel around quite a bit
these days.
Um and so, I was able to make it happen
and so, this is my
we are on the third themed cruise of
four total themed cruises. This we're in
the middle we're in the middle of Star
Trek right now. Cool. Um and then next
week is the '80s cruise.
Oh, that's going to be cool. Yeah, I'm
basically a floating um
I mean, audio engineer's like, a little
bit of it, but I'm kind of a floating
tech. So, I I'm a little bit of a Swiss
Army knife in the event world. I can
kind of like, fix the majority of
things. I can kind of I'm not like, the
best of the best at all these things,
but I'm good enough to like, I can fill
in, I can help you, and I'm just a hard
worker, and so I'm a I'm a floating role
essentially for this. Um
>> cool. Yeah.
And you get to see obviously some pretty
cool places that you that you haven't
been to. Yeah. Yeah. No, it it it it's a
gift. It's a It's It's been really cool,
man. It It is very funny. It's It I'm
having a lot of This last year is a lot
of those like man plans, God laughs. I
was actually trying to get back to the
Pacific Northwest. I was like
doing all these interviews, and I'm
doing third interviews and fourth
interviews, and it's like these
high-salary jobs, and I'm like, I'm
going to get back to the Pacific
Northwest, and I'm just going to get a
steady job, and it'll help these check
checklist things that I have going on.
It'll help those,
you know, be good.
And none of it was working out, and then
you know, the cruise ship stuff came up,
and it's been like such a great
enjoyable experience, and then I have
some other opportunities really coming
about in Austin for me, and so yeah,
it's a lot of this
man plans, God laughs situation
happening for me.
>> Yeah. I remember
me and Mark were talking, and we're
we're I was like, I think you visited or
something. I was like, "Hey, how's Jake
doing?" And he's like, "Uh is he still
planning on coming, you know, moving
back?" Cuz that was kind of what we
talked about previously. He's like, "No,
no, he's staying staying in Austin now.
He's going to go work on a cruise ship."
I was like,
"What?"
Yeah. [laughter]
So that's cool. Yeah, it it's
interesting, man. Um
as much as I
I'm actually accepting I don't know if
I'm supposed to say this on the podcast,
but I'm actually accepting a salary
position in Austin. Mhm. And it's really
not even like my first choice. It's
actually kind of a uh
It's a staging company that I'm like
I get a lot of purpose and like meaning
out of it. Like I really feel like this
place needs a good leader. This place
needs a good example. Um They need
someone who's positive. There's a lot of
negativity that can easily start flowing
in like the stage hand world. Mhm. And I
really bring out like a new a new light,
you know, just to like brag a little
bit, but like I really am cuz I'm I'm
intentional. I'm purposeful. Like if I'm
in a bad mood in the car, I'll get
myself in a good mood. I'm going to
listen to Tony Robbins on the way to the
gig. I'm going to like I'll smile in the
car to get my like I'm I'm I'm like,
"Hey, I'm here to serve these people and
they don't need a grumpy They
need someone who's positive,
encouraging." And so like I I work on
myself so I can go in and do that. And
um I I'm being put to use in that way.
It's not always easy. It's grueling
hours. Um some people really like don't
they don't get me, they don't like me.
But um
uh
I I'm being used like in a in a
I feel that this job that I'm going
towards is maybe it's not doesn't check
all my boxes of like these amazing
things and I'm making all this crazy
money. But it's like
I can be of service there in a way that
is genuinely useful. And um fulfilling
to everyone involved, you know? It's
kind of one of those things.
>> Yeah.
And you're you're learning and new
skills and kind of flexing those
those things you've learned along the
way and learning new stuff.
Which maybe that's part of the path, you
know? Yeah. Yeah. It's It's bringing out
sides of me that
um
I can be like I can be proud of in a
way, you know? Like I'm I'm just like
I'm in charge of like some some big
stuff. Like if I make the wrong decision
in in the single second I say the wrong
thing, then I just cost this company
thousands of dollars. Or or even worse,
I just put someone in danger
safety-wise, you know? Like so there's
>> It's cool to be called towards a certain
level of responsibility and to actually
um
you know, succeed at like do well at it.
Like like to look around and and go
like, "Damn, I'm you know, I'm actually
serving this role well, you know?" It's
It's something to be proud of. So,
yeah, it's been interesting though. I've
I didn't think I'd be in Texas this
long.
Yeah. Do you like it? I mean, Austin's
pretty cool town, but I've never been
there more than a vacation.
Yeah, I I love Austin. Austin is really
cool, man. It's um
It sucks to complain about this,
but like the heat really does get me,
I'll say. Oh, really? Yeah, I I've got
like these autoimmune disorders and
stuff in in my skin just hurts a lot in
the heat. Like heat just doesn't do well
with my skin. I get really inflamed and
like rashes and stuff.
Um,
but outside of that
Austin is so cool. There's so many cool
people. I'm surrounded by creatives and
artists and musicians and um
I get to
cuz I'm very
I'm not necessarily like type A. I'm
really like kind of ADHD creative, but
I've also like honed in on like when I
need to take care of and when I
need to be exact and in in proper. And
it's cool that like a lot of the work
that I've done on myself since I was
just a teenager, I'm able to like teach
these like 20-year-old kids and stuff.
Like, "Hey man, this is important. Hey
man, you think you're just a stagehand?
You're in customer service. You be
polite to that lady." Like all these
like little things that I've learned
that have helped me on my path, I get to
just show up and be myself and do well
at this job and I could tell these
people are listening. I have these young
guys who are like
Like bro, like if I'm if I'm teaching
them something
they're they're locked in. They're
listening. They know like, "Man, I've
got something to learn from this guy."
And so it's just it's just like a whole
circle of I I think I'm in the right
place for this time in my life for not
just me, you know? Yeah.
Yeah, I've got a I've had the
the uh
cool experience of having a couple like
apprentices and stuff at work and young
dudes. It's the same thing, you know,
you start you start teaching them and
then it's initially it's kind of like
this little bronco. He's just like
trying to do stuff, you know, like
what do you you know, you you kind of
got to come down on a little bit, but
you don't want to like scare them away.
Uh and then like you realize that a
couple months and then they're just like
like you're saying, they're just glued
in. They're like, "Oh yeah, okay. We're
going to do that? And it's going to be
like that? And then it's going to work?"
And I was like "Yep."
And then they they you see like their
little like their little like uh
confidence branches just start going
out. You're like
"All right. No more questions." It's
been like weeks since he's asked me for
anything. Hopefully he's not screwing
stuff up, but like
>> Go with God, young Padawan.
>> just assume he's he's fixing things now,
you know? Yeah. [laughter] Yeah.
Well, [clears throat] I mean that's
that's when when we're able to to teach
what we've learned and like impart it
with other people. Even if we're not
like saying I'm a teacher and I'm
teaching you this and you like you know
it's not like all about having a
slideshow with your like teaching
points, you know? It's like you show up.
You work on yourself so that when others
need to come up for air there you are,
you know? Like and that's even even in
just our skills, you know, we we find a
way to like if you were
fighting against your own demons and
like drinking before bed every single
night and you just wake up super
hungover, you're maybe you're going to
be a jerk to that guy and he's not going
to learn anything from you, you know
what I mean?
And so you working on yourself makes you
more open to
you know, little pieces of the puzzle of
puzzle that
other people might need. And especially
as a man, it does feel good I'll say to
you have younger men
listen to me, you know, in in a way that
like
like you know, they're they're getting
genuine help from what I'm offering them
and I like that.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, and for me it was kind of it was
tough like the first time I I was doing
it it was like I was getting frustrated
because I'm like
like it's it's he just you don't get it.
You you just you don't have the skills,
you don't have the this and that and
that. And I had to like have a major
like
internal moment where I'm like
yeah, idiot. He doesn't have the skills.
That's why you're here.
>> Yeah. You know, so I had to
Yeah, and like I have to
think about things like that. Like he
never went to school
like I did. He he's just like he's just
come up in the dealership or whatever,
you know, it's like
he doesn't have the foundation. And so
that's why I'm here. And so as much as I
want to be frustrated and like maybe
come down on him a little harder, I'm
like I have to like have the grace also
and just be like, "Hey,
let's let's work on this, you know, like
do you understand what I'm saying?" You
like start really like slowing it down,
which is tough, you know, in in this
industry or industry I work in, but you
know,
then they start talking back. You're
like, "Oh, okay." And I can kind of get
a depth for where they're at. But if I
seen it a lot in shops where
guys don't in that position, they don't
think like that. And it's just like, you
don't get it, dude. And then these these
kids that potentially could be a good
technician or whatever, they just
they get they you know, they just get
left by the wayside. They quit or
whatever else happens cuz no one takes
the time to really understand that
they're dumb. And I was dumb, too.
That's why we start with these these
type of things, you know, these
So
Sorry, go ahead.
Go ahead. I I mean, I was just saying
like if you never got to the point where
you're able to be humble enough as a man
and go, "You know what, man? I was dumb
and I was young and dumb once, too.
Let me help you out." If you never got
to that point, if you think you're if
you're all in your ego and like I'm the
and I you know, we've seen it
happen. I'm sure you've seen it happen
in your own ways as well at work is some
people will use that hierarchy of like,
"I know my shit." They'll use that as
like
a reaffirmation of that they're higher
in the hierarchy when they see a dumb
person. It's like, "Yeah, of course
you're an idiot. Let me I'm the only one
who could do this." And it's like you
you're keeping everyone below you so you
could feel higher than them. What the
is that? Yeah. You're just limiting
yourself. Yeah. Yeah. And and
the term I like to use when I'm when I'm
talking and teaching is like
I'll say like, "And don't do that
because this will happen.
Ask me how I know." And they're like,
>> [clears throat]
[laughter]
>> Yeah. Because I did that once, you know,
and I'm trying to help you and like
teach you like why this is, you know,
don't you know, torque it like that or
whatever cuz you're going to snap a bolt
off, you know, something. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Well, it man, it's the most actionable
thing to I think we live in this kind of
age where a lot of people um
you know, we demand change and like you
know, people are like you need to act
more like this and we need to be more
like this and it's like what like who
are you talking to? You're the adult in
the room. Like who who you you're
demanding like the government needs to
do this. Well, they're not your dad.
Like you're
we're
I think we like
we we don't think that we're the adults
in the room. Like at some point you got
to look around and go like oh, I'm the
oh, I'm the example.
And you got to really take
responsibility for it and that's a heavy
weight to bear, but it's the truth of of
what what's going on here. It's it
really is. Like if you're not going to
be the example, who is?
What is it just people in churches? Is
it just you really think like the
government should be the best example?
You're mad that the the president isn't
doesn't act this way, whatever and
you're going to spend your time like
whatever it is that you do with that.
It's like you could waste all of your
energy saying you guys need to be more
like this or you could be more like
this. Yeah. It's not about it's not
about pointing fingers, you know. We all
have to like step into our leadership
roles wherever they're at.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. And whatever yeah, whatever
opportunities and capacity that is. Uh
that's definitely something kind of to
what we've been talking about this theme
of
you know, symbols and signs and and you
know, things that they're the earth and
gives us.
It may be as simple as you know, you
know, taking somebody under your wing
for just a conversation or it may it
doesn't have to be with your trade, you
know? I remember
um
I guess it I was it was it was actually
like
towards the end of my like church days
like after high school I I remember we
were in this
this part of where like the everyone was
just kind of like talking and
introducing themselves to each other.
And the pastor is just like, "Hey,
you you know, um if you feel called to
it, you know, and just just pray for the
pray for each other, you know, and um
the guy he told me his name and stuff
and um
I started praying for him and then like
I started like
I was like, "Hey, you know?" And I
called him Dave. I was like, you know,
"Dave, I know he's probably going
through some relationship stuff or
something like that. He's stressed out."
And he just starts crying.
And I was just like
It was afterwards he's like, "Dude,
thank you. I'm like going through a
divorce and like I don't know what's
going to happen with the kids." He's
like, "And we just started talking, you
know, back and forth." He's like, "How
did you know?" I was like, "I
wasn't me. It wasn't me. But like
putting yourself in those positions,
um whether it's praying for somebody or
teaching somebody, you know, just being
that that vessel for light, basically. I
think that's
that's kind of like
the theme of and then it's not even just
a masculine thing. Like that's that's
just hu- being human. I think that's the
big the big thing to be open to.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Like we can't all
we can't always intellectually know
what's going on, but when we lean into
like these things of
yeah, maybe I don't know the outcome,
but I am going to
I'm going to try that. I'm going to I'm
going to try to pray, you know? I'm
going to try to to
Not that I
It's essentially like giving in to you
know what, dude, if I could somehow take
away your pain, I would. And I think
that's a truth that a lot of humans
have, like Mhm. we don't know how and
it's so like we just we know we see
suffering and we're like, "Dude, I know
I've been through that." And like
"Man, if I could take your pain away and
somehow like even just feel a little bit
of it for you, so you don't have to
carry so much, I would."
We I think a lot of humans I think it's
a natural thing all humans have, you
know, in a way.
But there's
we don't know how to do it. And I do
think that little thing like like prayer
or just being nice to someone or just
seeing when someone's struggling like
okay, he's not willing to admit he has
no idea how to use that power
tool,
>> [laughter]
>> but I'm going to go say, "Hey bud, give
that thing to me. Let me show you." You
know, like those little gestures, those
are what actually take a little bit of
their suffering away. And then it's not
like we take on their suffering and now
we have like
you know, like like we're wearing their
suffering around and we're feeling it
for them. We transmute it by doing that.
We dis hate their suffering by having
the courage, you know, courage is this
thing is we keep talking about
masculinity and men and men and stuff,
but courage is this thing like you need
to
buck up and run into the battlefield
with your sword. Sure, that's courage,
but also courage is the courage to
be willing to trip over your words, to
be willing to
even though this little is 19 and
he thinks he knows everything and he's
probably not really going to appreciate
how much I'm giving him right now, etc.
etc. I'm going to have the courage to
still trust the intuition that I should
go teach him a few things, that I should
go talk to him in this way. What
whatever like
I think I think real courage is
praying for Dave, you know. Mhm. Yeah.
Yeah. Answering
like answering the call and just being
open in that in that whatever that that
situation is, whether it's praying for
somebody or like we're talking about
teaching somebody. Mhm. Or just, you
know, even just witnessing people. I've
been there's been times where I maybe
for you too, you
driving you just see somebody on the
sidewalk and like my heart sinks
sometimes. I'm just like, "God." Almost
like seeing like the OG hobos, you know?
The OG like homeless. Like sometimes
you're just like, I just know that
person is just so down on their luck.
They just they really
are down on it and if
you just you just feel for them and you
pray for them or you just like you just
kind of feel whatever that was, you just
feel it and I'm There's been so many
times where I'm just like
spend spend a little time in those
moments just like witnessing them
and just like putting out good vibes and
you know, maybe pray for him.
Yeah, I think there's something very
real about that, you know, like if
they're
you know, like a homeless person for
example, if you can tell like man,
there's probably no there's no version
in their mind that is picturing them
in 5 years happy and healthy and loved
and in a warm home. Like they're
probably not thinking about that cuz
they're in a survival mindset. They're
just trying to, you know,
survive it and and do what they need to
do to get their food tonight. Like they
don't really have the
um they can't really afford in that
moment to like sit there and try to
think of a better future for themselves
maybe. And so maybe I'm going to bring
that possibility into this universe
right here and I'm just going to take 10
seconds and I'm going to say
I can't help you right now. Like I've
got to go to work. I don't have a bunch
of money to like give you a bunch of
money and solve all your problems. It's
just not the truth of my being. But I
can picture you happy. I can picture you
you nutrient dense and you've got more
more muscle and fat in your face cuz
you're not starving and I'm going to
picture you in a home and I'm going to
picture you married and happy and I feel
like
maybe it's a little dorky. Maybe it's a
little like wishful thinking, but I
don't know, maybe there's no opportunity
for that in the universe until you just
thought of it, you know. Like give them
think of them happy and healthy and
really like wish it, feel it in your own
body and send it towards them. There's
something about that, man. There's
something about it.
>> Yeah, I I I agree 100%. And if nothing
else, you've like you've given them like
a doorway.
Like the energy the energy doorway. Like
Something's going to happen. Something's
going to happen. You don't you don't
know what it is. You just you you pray
and hope for the best. But you know.
Yeah. I
I agree. Yeah. Yeah.
Um well, man, okay, so as we get up here
in time, I would like to I would like to
end for
I'm always thinking about the beginner
mindset on the podcast. I'm always
thinking about the people who are like
that they're coming to listen to us
because they're
you know, they're wanting to
self-improve. They're wanting to better
their life. They're wanting to
not be more like Jacob or Tim, but they
want to be more like, you know, their
version of the of their highest self. Um
can I ask you
how do you pray?
Like like do you drop to your knees at
your bed and you say things with your
mouth? Do you write? Like like can you
can you walk me through
how you pray?
Yeah. Um
I've taken it kind of like a
uh uh
a shamanistic approach to pray. Mhm. Um
[clears throat]
I don't think you need
It's it's one of those things like you
you can keep it super simple. You can
drop to your knees. Uh you can do it
while you're working. You can do it, you
know, whatever, but for me um
I'm just super big on intention.
Um and I think I think the universe and
God um in my in my belief, I think
that's the biggest key to anything. It's
just intention.
Um
so when I pray, I
I'll usually obviously I start with some
you know, a little bit of energy work,
little bit of breath work, and just to
for me to kind of, you know, drop in.
And
yeah, I I just uh for me, I fall I fall
to my knees. I pray on my knees. Um you
know, maybe kind of like a like a Muslim
would or something like that. Someone
who who follows, you know,
like that.
Um but, you know, it's you could I've
done it I do it both ways. I'll I'll
fall to my knees, my head down, or I'll
you know, kind of
crisscross, you know, like kind of like
a meditation pose.
Um
and
for me with prayer
I like to
I like to start and end my prayer with
gratitude.
So,
I know it sometimes is tough when you're
going through stuff and you just want to
be like,
"Help me. I need this and and I'll help
me out." But,
I think if again to it the intention is
is is the space and the energy, you
know, with with um
with whatever the the deity or the
energy is. For me it's creator, God. Um
so I just, you know, there's just
thanks. There's thanks. There's
gratefulness. And and then, you know, it
depending on what
what kind of flows at that point, it
just kind of that rolls out. Um whether
it's um "This has been on my heart. I'm
praying for this."
Or um you know, "Guide me this way." You
know, and also I pray for my future
self.
Pray for future self. Um
you know, and and pray for
um
the way you want, you know, God to um
like
shape you into the person that, you
know, you you're you're down here to be.
Um you know, and if you don't know what
that is, just pray for it. Like, "God, I
don't know
I don't know what what I'm here for."
Like a lot of us, I think that's the
question, right?
Um so so, you know, "Give me guidance to
whatever, you know, whatever that is,
you know, show me my purpose." Uh
and then I think
once you start that that dialogue, like
we're talking about with the signs and
the symbols, you'll start to see things
like
you know, for me it's community. For me
it's um
you know, it's it's faith. Um community
and um
so that's
whatever that is, that's like for my
future self, I pray for it.
Um and maybe that changes over time, but
I just know in my soul right now that's
like why I'm here.
That's one of my my one of my my uh
I guess one of I wouldn't say talent,
but it's like, you know, one of the
things that God's like, "Yeah, this is
you and this is what you're supposed to
be doing." Um and so like living that
living a life towards towards those
things, um
which requires the like we talked about
the ego death and especially when
it's um
it's tough when you you're maybe living
outside of of of your capacity of what
you're really supposed to be doing.
You're like, "This is why everything's
so hard is cuz I'm not living
the way I'm supposed to. This is I'm not
designed to be doing this." Yeah. Um
So yeah, pray for your future self.
Um
and then
depending on, you know, where you're at,
for me I I like to um
I like to like to call on support.
So I'll I'll pray for I'll pray for
energies um
from other
you know, like don't don't sleep on the
ancestors, homie, you know? Like
seriously, like, [clears throat] you
know, I I I I I I I I I I
I I pray for I pray for, you know, help
and and wisdom from from ancestors um
and from my from both sides of my my
lineage and
you know, I I do I do I do give rules
when I'm when I'm praying for praying
for and with maybe other energies. Um
you know, I I pray for, you know,
ancestors with, you know, good
intentions and good um
good faith and and light cuz you don't
want to to attach yourself to some some,
you know,
some bad dude from back in the day.
[laughter]
Yeah, yeah, yeah. But [clears throat]
yeah, so Yeah, use me for good. Yeah,
exactly. You know, like
uh I'm a big proponent to that for
angels, you know, again back to
energies.
You know,
and then
there's just a lot of reverence and and
thanks for just
you know, creator.
And I just I just there's a lot of
thanks. And then then back to the
gratitude and
um
I also pray for
just a continual
uh
relationship with
you know, with creator in in this God in
this in this
example.
Yeah.
>> Um just to always have that that I
always want to be seeking and I always I
always want to
um invite you know, God to the space. In
this in this in this case it's prayer.
You know, in this in this little my
living room or whatever it is.
So, just always asking for that
relationship and always um
being thankful. So, gratitude I guess
it's gratitude and thankfulness is how I
start and my prayers.
Um and then everything in the middle.
Yeah, I
I kept thinking like asking you shall
receive, you know,
like like if you ask for guidance like
man, I don't know what's going on, but
help me, you know, whether yeah, what
whatever your language is for that. And
I will say the gratitude thing.
I love [snorts] that you said that like
that is really there's a lot of
meditation teachers, there's a lot of
modern neuroscientists, like there's a
lot of like I mean it's at the point
where like I can give you data on what
happens in your body when we practice
gratitude. Um and and I also connect it
to so like Tony Robbins talks very
eloquently and also Jordan Peterson they
talked very well about like
you know, a way of defining depression
is thinking about yourself.
And it's this like weird thing and that
sounds too sensitive
insensitive whatever. Um
but
that is kind of a way out of breaking
the thought patterns of like me and I'm
suffering and this happened to me and I
can't get better and life is hard for me
and all these things that like again,
I've been there a million times. Like
it's it's a hard it's a part of being a
human. But if I stop and I you know, I
fall to my knees or whatever
whatever I'm doing and I think of
friends that I love and I say, "Uh
you know, Dave or you know, Andrew's
going through this thing right now and
God I don't know what it looks like and
I don't even know if this whole praying
thing works, but can you please can you
help him? Can you reach out into his
life and can you help him?"
And and then you're you're like you
start maybe visualizing that. Like
picture your friend happy. Picture your
friend like fulfilled in their problem.
Whatever they're going through, maybe
you know personally what they're going
through. And you say, "Hopefully like
you know, God be with them for that."
And you could feel it well up in your
body and suddenly you're not thinking
about yourself even just for a few
seconds. And I feel like that is we're
talking about that metaphorical door. I
think when we get out of our own way of
thinking about me me me me me, help me,
fix me, fix me, I'm broken. We open up
this door for like this frequency to
come in
that starts to heal us through that
opening of um
hopefulness for someone else, of
thankfulness for what we have, of of
gratitude. I mean like it's it's very
easy. Even if you have nothing, you can
look around even if you're the homeless
person on the street, you can say
"God, thank you for at least giving me
these old shitty pair of shoes, you
know, it's better than burning my feet
on the pavement, you know." Yep. And um
you know, that's real that's really low
and that's very very different from what
most of us are used to, but like me, you
know, dude, I can if I'm caught up in
being suffering and like life's not
going my way, I forget that like when
I'm at my apartment at home
I'm surrounded by like the dopest of
dope DJ gear and equipment that somehow
I've been able to purchase and I have
these cool clothes and I have in my
thermostat goes to 67 whenever I want it
to. Like holy like you know what I
mean? Like if you could just it seems so
silly and easy and cheap and all those
things, but I really think there is some
magic in the gratitude of bro, name your
things. Name Hey, I'm glad that I like
Hey, I got some extra teriyaki sauce for
free yesterday and they didn't charge me
for it when I when I bought it.
Hey, that that cute girl that I was
that cute girl like smiled at me for a
little bit yesterday when when she was
serving me my my food or whatever. Like
find little things, whatever they may
look like, to trigger that gratitude.
And like you said, man, so elegantly,
like
the gratitude really is I think it opens
the door in in an unreal way. just
>> Yeah.
Name things in your life. Start going
through them in your head. Even if
you're suffering, stop trying to solve
it all in your head. But what can you be
grateful for? What can you be thankful
for? And maybe you can only think of
three things right now. That's okay.
Whatever you can do, you know, it's it's
you open the window at least a crack and
I think there's legitimate magic in
that.
I I agree, 100%. And one thing that also
I forget
to pray about, but I always do it.
And I think people sleep This is another
slept on thing.
Is always spend some time
like
what we're talking about with gratitude
and thankfulness,
spend that same time
thinking about that and praying about
that for your body.
Like God, I'm grateful for this body,
for this vessel, you know, like that I
can be on this earth, you know, and
and then start praying, you know,
praying for your body, like, you know,
thank you, you know, thank you for my my
my blood that is, you know, cleaning and
giving life to my organs and everything
like that, you know, like I and then,
you know, even just affirmations, like
when you're praying, like, you know, my
body is healthy, my body is strong.
You know, cuz I think a lot of people
it's assumed almost, like, yeah, my
body, you know, whatever, but like it's
it's this is this is our vessel, this is
our vehicle, you know, like
and you know, this this is our
attachment to God, so, you know,
on top of all the physical side of
things, you know, obviously with like
diet and everything else that you want
to like obviously try to like
you know, tailor something that makes
makes you healthy.
Um, it's just it's just one of those
spiritual things that I I think people
don't Maybe they do. I don't know. I
don't know everyone's prayers, but
uh it's just something that I I like to
really add into my prayer is is always
always being very thankful, very
very having a lot of gratitude for um
your your body.
Yeah. Yeah. I like the I like the you
included that, man, cuz I I think uh
as someone who like deals with chronic
stuff,
I can sometimes get caught up in like
why? Why am I dealing with this? Like
can I I just want to get better, like,
you know? But I can pray for the things
that aren't like Dude, I have two eye I
have eyesight and it it works pretty
well. And I can smell delicious waffles,
like we talked about. Um, and and like I
don't get to experience the feeling of
like awe at a beautiful sight without
these eyes. Like thank you, God, for
these eyes, for giving me
a moment of awe to where I feel small
and I go I don't know what this is all
about, but this feels really good, you
know? Like Yeah, thank you for this body
and the experience that it gives me.
That's very well said, man.
Yeah. Yeah.
Um, okay, brother. Uh we're getting up
here in time. I should probably get back
to work. Uh see if any fires need put
out. Uh hopefully they burned out while
I was away.
Um,
I want to thank you again for for your
time and uh in doing this again with me,
buddy. Thank you so much. Yeah, thanks
for, you know, al- always taking my my
call and uh and providing providing this
platform, you know, for
you know,
people just to like talk about this
stuff. Like you're you're really doing a
lot of good and helping people.
Hopefully, man. Yeah, I uh I selfishly I
I just love doing this thing, and so I'm
I'm glad I'm glad it helps people, you
know? So,
uh
Well, I'll be hitting you up cuz I'm
I want to start I want to start uh my
own little podcast, too. Ooh. So, I'll
be hitting you up for some some tips and
tricks and what what gear what gear and
stuff cuz I'm tired of looking at
YouTube videos.
Yeah, no, dude. I will happily help you.
I would love to 100% please. Yeah, let
let's chat. I'm on this
Let's see. I've got like two more weeks
on this cruise.
And then I do have a little bit more
travel work, but I'll be
more available. So, call me anytime.
Stay in touch.
And yeah, let let's get that ball
rolling, man. I can probably Nowadays,
you really don't have to spend too much.
There's a lot of simplified like a lot
of tools these days that like really
simplify even like making clips and you
know, AI to like help you write bios if
that's your thing. Like there's there's
a lot of cool stuff that I would love to
give you if you want to explore more on
the podcasting too, man. That'd be
awesome.
>> Totally open.
Yeah, sure. Yeah.
All right, Tim Reilly. I appreciate you,
brother.
Have a good rest of your day. Listeners,
you know the drill. If you are listening
right now and you haven't drank any
water today, what's your problem? Drink
some water. If you haven't stretched
today, what are you doing, dog? Get on
your knees and stretch. And try out some
prayer. Whatever prayer means to you,
however it works for you. Maybe you
could try Tim's way. Maybe you could try
some of the ways that I rambled on
about, but
give it a rip. Give it a little bit of a
try. And you know, love yourselves,
dammit. So,
Tim, thanks again, buddy. I'm going to
end this recording.
Thanks, brother.
Hello and welcome to the Junkyard Love
podcast.
It's all good. It's all good. The
Junkyard Love podcast.
>> [music]
[music]
>> four
the Junkyard Love